麦克 · 诺斯: 和或者操作员。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: The and and or operators.
所以我在这里创建了两种类型
So I've created two types here and
一个叫做 HasPhoneNumber，一个叫做 HasName。
one is called HasPhoneNumber,
one is called HasName.
他们有共同点，也有不同的地方，对吧？
They have something in common and they
have something that's different, right?
把这个想象成一个维恩图，对吗？
So think of this as a Venn diagram, right?
他们都有名字，但一个有电子邮件，一个有电话。
They both have name but
one has email and one has phone.
这里我创建了一段代码基本上是在掷骰子,
So, here I've created a piece of
code that basically rolls the dice,
做了一个数学运算，随机的。
does a math.random.
有一半的时间，它会将其初始化为有声数字。
And half the time, it's gonna
initialize it to HasPhoneNumber.
有一半的时间，它会将其初始化为 HasEmail。
Half the time,
it's gonna to initialize it to HasEmail.
事实上，打字稿应该可以算出，不幸的是,
And, in fact, TypeScript should be able
to figure out, well unfortunately,
所以我才把它留在那里。
that's why I left that there.
这是同一种类型，但它只是使它难看，对不对？
It's the same type, but
it just makes it ugly, right?
所以在这里，我们得到了好名字，HasEmail 或 HasPhoneNumber。
So here, we get the nice names,
HasEmail or HasPhoneNumber.
我们要把它搬走,
We're moving that, okay, I mean,
从某种程度上来说是有点准确，但是
that's It's kinda accurate in a way, but
不是我真正想要的，而是更加冗长。
like not really what I was after,
and way more verbose.
迈克 · 诺斯: 所以请注意，一旦我们有了这个联系方式
&gt;&gt; Mike North: So
note that once we have this contact info
变量，我们只能访问名称。
variable, we can only access name.
假设你有这样的维恩图，它可以
So, think of this as if you have this
sort of Venn diagram, and it could
不管是一边还是另一边，我们看到的是两者之间的交集。
be one side or the other, we are looking
at the intersection between the two.
我们正在研究这种镜头。
We're looking at sort of that lens.
我们只能访问那些保证存在的东西。
We can only access things that
are guaranteed to be there.
不管这是 HasName 还是 HasName
And regardless of whether
this is HasName or
Hasphonenumber，名字会出现在那里。
HasPhoneNumber, name is going to be there.
这就是为什么我们可以访问名字和唯一的名字。
So that's why we can access name and
only name.
联合类型，他们使用这个和运算符和百分比价值和。
Union types, they use this and
operator and percentage worth and.
这实际上就是说。
And this is saying effectively.
其他联系信息包括一个 HasEmail 和一个 HasPhoneNumber。
Other contact info is both a HasEmail and
also a HasPhoneNumber.
所以必须用这两个形状的所有东西来初始化它。
So it must be initialized with
everything these two shapes have.
结合，这将是完整的维恩图，两个气泡。
The union, this will be the full
Venn diagram, both bubbles.
所以，如果我们遗漏了一件事情，你会说，财产‘电话’丢失了。
So if we were missing one thing you
would say, Property 'phone' is missing.
迈克 · 诺斯: 因为我们保证这三样都有
&gt;&gt; Mike North: And because we're
guaranteed to have all three of these
这些东西，我们都能进入，对吗？
things, we can access all three of them,
right?
没有模棱两可，没有二者之一，或者两者都是。
There's no ambiguity, there's no either or
it's definitely both.
迈克 · 诺斯: 所以，对不起，我把那个留在那里了。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: So in this,
sorry I left that there.
这是上一次运行的一个例子。
That was an example from a previous run.
我们在这里重述一下，我们讨论了变量。
So just to recap here,
we covered variables.
我们研究了打字稿是如何从到推断变量的类型的
We looked at how typescript could
infer the type of variable through
它被初始化了。
it being initialized.
我们研究了数组和元组。
We looked at arrays and tuples.
这些是有序的数据结构。
Those are the ordered data structures.
一、数组的长度是任意的。
One, the array is arbitrary is length.
另一个 tuple 具有固定的长度和
The other, tuple, has a fixed length and
元组中每个元素的特定类型。
a specific type for
each element in the tuple.
我们查看了对象类型。
We looked at object types.
你唯一需要记住的就是问号的意思
And really the only thing you have to
remember there is question mark means
可选的。
optional.
最后，等价于或和
And then finally,
the equivalent of or and and
在类型世界中，交集和并运算符。
in the type world,
the intersection and union operators.